Final Episode
Earth, the Yamato is…
The floating fragments of Area 550 have
taken a descending trajectory into the Moon.
Moving on to Area 551.
Reload magnetron probes.
Reloading magnetron probes.
What a mess…
Current moon surface rebuild rate, 7.5%.
A half year since the war with Gatlantis…
Okita Juzo
Commander
Promotion, huh ?
It's the Yamato.
That's correct, Mr. Sanada.
You pick the people.
I want you to find out what's going on.
It's hard to believe,
but if it's really the Yamato…
Kodai !
Kodai…
This is Yamazaki !
I found a survivor !
It's alive.
Over here.
Yamamoto !
There you are.
Two sets of memories merge…
Anything can happen here.
Kodai.
Kodai…
It's a projection.
Kodai's over there right now.
I saw a tree.
It was so big that I couldn't
see the top or its base.
That's how Teresa sees
the flow of time, she says.
Maybe that's Teresa herself.
Did you talk to Teresa ?
No, it could have been my brother,
Tsurumi, or even Klaus.
Things like who or where
are ambiguous in that world.
But I was asked to relay her message,
and I remember it clearly.
Those two could have come home
if they wished, but they didn't.
That's why…
Klaus Keyman
Klaus was tossed left and right by his fate, but he achieved salvation by going onboard the Yamato and meeting you.
It's not going to be easy, but I'll do
my best to respond to her message.
When the Ark of Destruction disappeared...
...a tremendous energy was released,
but it didn't have any impact on Earth.
Teresa merged with the Yamato...
...and pushed the annihilation energy
away beyond the dimensional horizon.
That makes sense.
The reaction pushed the
Yamato into a higher dimension.
The basis for your argument is weak.
It's just one surviving pilot, after all.
Nevertheless, I'm with you.
So many have died.
We don't have enough crews.
Yet, we keep building ships.
No matter what the future holds for Earth,
everyone's come to realize the path is unfavorable.
We found a dimensional node deep behind
the water wall where the Yamato surfaced.
There's another fault deep
within the Time Fault.
In the deepest fault, time has been so infinitely stretched that humans can't measure it.
The Yamato's come back from that fault, leaving
Captain Kodai and Operational Chief Mori behind.
Do you mean…
Yes, they're both alive.
I've been sent to relay a message that the course of
the future will return to normal by bringing them back.
How could that be possible ?
Is it possible to back track
the route the Yamato has taken ?
It doesn't require any energy to descend
from a higher dimension to our dimension.
However, in order for us to ascend…
…simply put, we need near infinite energy.
Infinite…
Then, we have no means…
We still have a way…
...with the help of the Ginga.
The damage would be severe...
...but if we use the Ginga's CRS amplifier again,
we can compress the excess dimensions of the fault.
In other words, we induce a collapse
of dimensions inside the fault.
Using the collapsing force to launch
the Yamato into the higher dimension.
The Time Fault would be like
a balloon with a sudden loss of air.
It'll collapse and disappear.
How absurd !
It's a tall order to sacrifice the
Time Fault to save two people, isn't it ?
Yeah.
It's totally unreasonable.
But on the political side, a miracle might
occur thanks to Ambassador Barrel's efforts.
The last war shocked the political scene.
Reveal everything and
call for a national vote…
The impossible might actually happen.
National vote ?
We can't swing the vote, and
the odds are still against us.
But what if that can correct
the path of the future ?
We might be being tested.
Kodai, what're you doing now ?
The planets only stay in their locations.
Only you can turn them
into meaningful entities…
…with the heart to admire their beauty.
Your soul nurtures love,
and love resonates to build fate.
It becomes entwined with many to
weave what you call time and space.
But excessive love can sometimes…
You can still see your future.
Now, open your eyes.
Things could have been different.
Things can be different.
Everything's determined by your desire.
You can have your ideal world if you so wish.
But I pulled the trigger.
And I'll keep losing precious things
by repeating the same action.
Please take a look at the night scenery of the
capital, which has been restored thus far.
Energy, material, military power…
All of them are crucial for our future.
And it's all supported by the Time Fault.
Consider the meaning of destroying it.
We should put all our emotions aside...
...and take the next 100 years of Earth's
prosperity into account, before making a decision.
Shima, aren't you going
to hear the next speech ?
We've got things to do.
Let's go.
Yuria…
Okay.
It's the third hangar.
It's all ready.
Let's get going.
I envy you guys.
Let me talk about a man.
He's an ordinary man
you can find anywhere.
He loves people, and believes
in the society built by people.
When Earth faced the danger of destruction, he joined the great journey to Iscandar.
After returning home, he broke his back for the
restoration of Earth just like each and every one of you.
His only wish was to keep
our promise with Iscandar.
However, the situation of the post-war
Earth didn't allow him to do so.
He must have felt the
sense of betrayal.
That's why, when we received
a message from Telezart…
…he didn't hesitate to respond, despite
the risk of being accused of revolt.
He wanted to be faithful to his belief that we, the people of Earth, should keep the peace of the universe.
In the end, he had to pull the trigger of the wave
motion gun more frequently than anyone else.
In order to survive, in order to protect,
he had to betray what was in his heart.
He did try to resist, using every
available opportunity to seek peace.
He even stood in front of an enemy
who was pointing a gun at him.
But everything turned out negatively,
and he had to turn his life into a weapon.
It saved Earth, but that's just hindsight.
He, and Mori Yuki, who loved him
and met the same fate, are not heroes.
He's you.
Failing to realize our dreams,
we feel the sense of loss every day.
We're used to deceiving ourselves in
the name of survival and responsibility.
We've lost our true selves.
Even though we know yesterday's mistake
and today's compromise will erode our future…
…we keep walking on the
path which leads to nowhere.
He's another self of you and I,
who must live through this difficult time.
That's why you shouldn't feel obliged.
It's wrong to think that the sacrifice is
justifiable just because they're heroes.
If you think you can save
yourself by saving them…
…if you think this absurd choice
can lead to our true future…
…then please vote to rescue both of them.
Please don't let the voices for convenience and
efficiency deceive you, but follow your heart.
That's our only future.
This is bad.
It's branched out so widely
that it'll eventually dry up.
Dry up ?
There must be a force so strong
that it can break the flow of time.
Even though the
Ark of Destruction was destroyed ?
That wasn't enough.
Intelligent life-forms, like humans,
have a great responsibility to the universe.
We're given a mechanism called a soul
to fulfill it, but it's complex and fragile.
Sometimes it nurtures despair,
and halts our walk forward.
Kodai !
Kodai.
Kodai, how much longer are you going to be like that ?
Kodai !
Kodai, come over here !
Yuki, no, I can't.
No matter how hard I try
to find a different future…
…only the perpetual cycle of
pulling the trigger is left for us.
No !
I don't want this sense
of loss anymore, so…
I don't want it either, so Kodai…
Kodai…
Kodai Susumu saved Earth !
He did it before...
...and he will do it
over and over again !
No matter how badly he's beaten...
...he'll always do that because
he has Mori Yuki by his side !
That's one of many futures.
But it's the only future that awaits you.
Future…
The path to the future is restored.
The future will eventually be gone.
The universe will eventually use up
its energy, then cool down and die.
But that's not everything.
Life and human intelligence can re-create it…
…as long as we envision
the universe in our souls.
That's the duty of humans, who
know how to love with their hearts.
Eternal warmth keeps
on protecting the universe.
Let's go home, Yuki.
The planets only stay in their locations.
Only humans can turn them
into meaningful entities…
…with the heart to admire their beauty.
In the infinitely expansive universe,
there exists various kinds of life.
Stars die and stars arise.
The heartbeat of this vast universe is
passed on from one life to another...
...and it will never come to an end.
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Yamato
The End